masseffectarchives.com 2019-12-30

# None

**Last Updated: December 9, 2019  
Effective Date: December 9, 2019  
**

## 1\. Information We Collect

The information we collect depends on what Services you use and how you use them. Please see below for more details.

  1. Information You Give Us Directly

We collect information that you provide us, including:

    * Your EA Account information, including your email address, username, real name, country, date of birth, telephone number and password;
    * Security questions and answers;
    * Details you provide in response to surveys about our Services;
    * Information you provide when seeking help from us such as your name, telephone number and records (including call recordings) of the issues you experience; and
    * Billing information, such as your name, payment card number, payment account details, and shipping address;
  2. Information You Provide When Playing Online

When you participate in social features such as chat, the audio, visual, and electronic information that you disclose may become publicly available. It also may be read, copied, collected, or used by other players. Please make sure your privacy settings reflect your preferences.

When you participate in online multiplayer games, your in-game profile information, gameplay, and statistics are visible to all. In some of our racing titles, when you play certain multiplayer modes we may record your gameplay and replay it to other players to race against. In competitive game modes, such as FUT Champions, we may record your gameplay, and your controller button inputs, and replay these together with your in-game profile information and game statistics to other players in-game and at live EA or partner events.

  3. Other Information We Collect When You Use Our Services

We may collect other information automatically when you use our Services, including:

    * IP address;
    * Mobile and other hardware or device identifiers;
    * General geolocation data (derived from IP or device settings);
    * Browser information, including your browser type and the language you prefer;
    * Referring and exit pages, including landing pages and pages viewed and other interactions with web content;
    * Platform type;
    * Information about your device, hardware and software, such as your hardware settings and components, EA software and updates you have installed or use, and presence of required plugins;
    * Details about what EA games or Services you purchase or obtain, and your use of them;
    * Inferences regarding your preferences, predispositions, behavior, abilities, and aptitudes;
    * Device event information, including crash reports, request and referral URLs and system activity details (e.g. whether you encountered an error playing our games or lost Internet access);
    * Biometric information (for specific applications such as face-scanning apps); and
    * Other information (such as your likeness) that you may provide as part of your participation in live events.

  4. We also may collect and store information locally on your device, using mechanisms like cookies, browser web storage (including HTML 5) and application data caches.
  5. Information Provided to Us by Third Parties

 **PlayStation®3 & PlayStation®4 Computer Entertainment Systems. **By signing up to use EA online Services on a PlayStation®3 or PlayStation®4 computer entertainment system, you agree your Account of PlayStation™Network information will be provided to EA so we can establish an EA Account for you. You need an EA Account to access EA's online Services. From Sony, we receive information including your name, email address, Online ID, your country, state or province, language and date of birth. We do not receive your credit card number or other financial information.

 **Xbox Live.** By signing up to use EA online Services on Microsoft's Xbox Live Service, you agree that Microsoft may provide us with your Microsoft user account information so we can establish an EA Account for you. You need an EA Account to access EA's online Services. From Microsoft, we receive information including your Gamertag, email address, state or province, country, language and age. We do not receive your credit card number or other financial information.

 **Wii / Wii U.** By signing up to use EA online Services on a Nintendo Wii or Wii U console, you agree that Nintendo may provide us with your Nintendo user account information so we can establish an EA Account for you. You need an EA Account to access EA's online Services. From Nintendo, the data we receive includes your Mii information, email address, Nintendo Network ID, friend list, country, language and date of birth. We do not receive your credit card number or other financial information.

 **Nintendo Switch™.** By signing up to use EA online Services on a Nintendo Switch™ console, you agree that Nintendo may provide us with your Nintendo Account information so we can establish an EA Account for you. You need an EA Account to access EA's online Services. From Nintendo, the data we receive includes your nickname, email address, friend list, country, language and date of birth. We do not receive your credit card number or other financial information.

 **Mobile Platforms.** If you play or purchase our games on your mobile device and/or tablet, we receive information about you from the app stores and other mobile platform providers. This information includes your username and/or device ID and the fact that you made a purchase, for instance, but does not include any sensitive or financial information. Some of our mobile platforms also may send information to us that you authorize them to provide. Our mobile games also may request additional personal information from you, such as push notification tokens, your precise location or contact list, and we will collect this information only if you give us your explicit consent.

 **Other Third Parties**

We may receive information from third parties, like Facebook or Game Center, when you use these services in our games. We may also receive information about you when other players choose to share their contact lists with us.

We also may receive information from third parties to supplement the information we receive from you. We use information from these companies primarily to help us deliver relevant advertising to you. A list of these types of third parties can be found on [privacyappendix.ea.com](https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBPRIVACYAPPENDIX/US/en/PC/). We also may use information from third parties, for instance, to help us understand your approximate geolocation via your IP address for tax purposes, or to customize certain Services to your location, and for fraud or abuse prevention purposes.

  6. Legal Basis for Processing

If you are a resident of the European Union, we rely on a number of legal grounds to process information about you. For example, we will process information about you where we have your consent, where we have a legitimate interest to do so, where the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, and where we have a legal obligation to process your information. For example, we rely on our legitimate interests to serve targeted marketing for our Services and on contractual necessity to process information when you create an EA Account. To learn more about the legal grounds on which we rely to process your information for any particular purpose, please contact us via the options in Section 11 below.  

## 2\. How We Collect Information

We and third parties use technologies described below to collect information to deliver excellent experiences.

  1. Cookies and Similar Technologies

Cookies are small text files stored on your Internet browser. We use cookies and similar technologies to help us understand things like what web pages, features or ads you view and what games you play. This information helps us keep track of your shopping cart, measure the effectiveness of our advertising, make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly and otherwise help enhance your player experience. You can disable cookies, limit the types of cookies you allow, or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent. Please refer to guidance provided by your individual web browser if you'd like help in managing your cookie preferences.

We use other technologies for similar purposes as a cookie. We use tracking pixels or clear GIFs to collect information about your use of our Services and your response to our marketing emails. We use Internet log files (which contain technical data such as your IP address) to monitor traffic on our Services, troubleshoot technical problems, detect and prevent fraud, and enforce our User Agreement. Other examples include HTML 5 cookies, Silverlight Application Storage, device fingerprints and "flash cookies." If you want to remove flash cookies or prevent them from being placed, adjust your preferences in the Macromedia Website Privacy Settings Panel at [www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/](https://www.macromedia.com/support/documentation/en/flashplayer/help/). We currently do not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals. You may opt out of certain types of tracking, including certain analytics and tailored advertising, by changing your cookie settings.

We also use Analytics, Advertising, Anti-Cheat and Anti-Fraud technologies in our Services that utilize the same cookies and similar mechanisms. These technologies are described below.

  2. Analytics Technologies

We use our own game servers and internal and third party analytic technologies to collect information about how you use our Services, your computer or device and the health of our Services.

For instance, EA may collect and store data from your computer or device when you use our Services. This information includes technical and related information about your computer or device and operating system (such as IP Address and device ID), information about your feature usage, gameplay and usage statistics, system interactions and peripheral hardware for purposes described in Section 3, below. If you play a game offline, this data will be stored on your device and transmitted to EA when your device connects to the Internet. If you participate in online Services, EA also may collect, use, store, transmit and publicly display your persona and/or statistical data regarding your game play (including scores, rankings and accomplishments), or identify content that is created and shared by you with other players.

Third party analytics technologies integrated into our Services may combine the information they collect in connection with EA's Services with information they have independently collected over time and across different websites. Many of these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies. A list of third party analytics companies that operate in our Services as well as how to opt out to the extent applicable can be found at [privacyappendix.ea.com](https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBPRIVACYAPPENDIX/US/en/PC/).

  3. Ad Serving Technologies

Some of our Services employ ad serving technologies that use cookies, clear GIFs, web beacons, tracking pixels, and other similar technologies (" **Technologies** ") to deliver offers to you. Some of these technologies can sync or connect behavior across different websites, mobile apps and devices. The ads can be tailored to your interests. For instance, you may be presented with an offer for a game we think you might enjoy. Or if you express interest in a game, you might receive an advertisement later for that game or similar Services on EA or third party sites. Other in-game advertising technologies enable advertising to be temporarily uploaded to your game, web browser, or mobile device and later replaced while you are online.

These technologies collect and use information so we can serve appropriate advertising to you and help track results and measure effectiveness. In addition to identifiers, this information includes:

    * Advertisements served and the location of the ad;
    * Length of time an advertisement was visible;
    * Domain type, IP address, size of the advertisement; and
    * Advertisement response.
  4. Third party advertising companies may combine the information collected in the context of delivering an ad to you via our Services with other information they have independently collected over time and across different websites. Many of these companies collect and use information under their own privacy policies. A list of ad serving companies that operate their own networks on our sites and online and/or mobile games and/or Services as well as how to opt out to the extent applicable can be found at [privacyappendix.ea.com](https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBPRIVACYAPPENDIX/US/en/PC/).

To learn more about some of these ad networks' practices, or to opt out of third party targeted advertising, you can visit [www.networkadvertising.org](https://www.networkadvertising.org/), [www.aboutads.info/choices](https://www.aboutads.info/choices/), [youradchoices.ca](http://youradchoices.ca/), or [www.youronlinechoices.eu](https://www.youronlinechoices.eu/). Note that opting out does not mean you won't see ads; it just means that the advertising you see may be less relevant to your interests.

  5. Anti-Cheat and Fraud Prevention Technologies

EA strives to provide a safe and fair gaming environment for all players. When you log in to one of our Services, set up an EA Account or make purchases, we or third parties may use cookies and similar technologies, or collect data about your machine or device, to create a machine "fingerprint" or "hash" of your machine components, for fraud prevention, security and authentication purposes. We may also monitor publicly-available information, third party sites and/or use anti-cheat technology with our Services, including automated anti-fraud and abuse algorithms. If you believe your access to our games and/or Services was blocked by this technology in error, please contact EA Help at [help.ea.com](https://help.ea.com/en/).  

## 3\. How We Use Your Information

We use your personal and non-personal information, both individually and combined together, in the following ways:

 **To operate our business and to enhance and personalize your game experience including to:**

  * Operate, improve, and develop our games and Services;
  * Undertaking research for technological development and demonstration;
  * Provide you with personalized recommendations for EA games and/or Services;
  * Populate online leaderboards and enable online matchmaking;
  * Provide replays to you and other players via spectator modes;
  * Help you find your friends or tell your friends about an EA game or Service;
  * Facilitate sharing on social networks;
  * Serve and measure the effectiveness of advertising;
  * Measure the health of our Services;
  * Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent or illegal activity, and prosecute those responsible for that activity;
  * Set up and maintain accounts you register for;
  * Provide game experiences that you may like;
  * Set up loyalty programs;
  * Facilitate your gameplay on multiple devices when available;
  * Identify, fix, and troubleshoot bugs and Service or functionality errors;
  * Provide software updates;
  * Activate or authenticate your games and save game progress and stats;
  * Run competitions and contests;
  * Performing audits related to interactions, transactions and other compliance activities;
  * Other purposes you consent to, are notified of, or are disclosed when you provide personal information;
  * Adhere to your preferences and to deliver dynamic content; and
  * Help keep our Services safe and fair, resolve disputes, investigate and help curb fraud and illegal behavior, comply with the law, and to enforce our agreements and policies.

**To provide you support, including to:**

  * Help identify and troubleshoot problems with your account or games;
  * Survey your opinions through surveys or questionnaires;
  * Communicate with you and respond to your specific requests or questions; and
  * Manage and send you confirmations and important information about your account, Services, purchases, subscriptions, and warranties.

**To personalize our communications with you, including to:**

  * Present offers and/or information relating to games you might like;
  * Make recommendations to you; and
  * Personalize advertising for you and deliver targeted marketing, service updates and promotional offers.  

We retain the information we collect for as long as necessary to provide our Services, and we may retain that information beyond that period if necessary for legal, operational or other legitimate reasons.

## 4\. Information We Share with Third Parties

We do not share, sell, or disclose your personal information, other than with the categories of third parties listed below. For a list of the categories of personal information we have sold or disclosed about consumers for a business purpose in the past 12 months, please contact us as set forth in Section 11 below. We do not sell the personal information of players under 16 years of age without affirmative authorization.

**Service providers.** We employ third parties located in and outside of your country of residence (including outside of the European Economic Area (EEA)) to collect or process personal information on our behalf for the purposes described in Section 3 above, including but not limited to conducting market surveys, IT and related services, facilitating credit card processing, facilitating live events, or sending emails. When our third party agents or service providers collect or receive personal information, we require that they use the data only on our behalf and for purposes consistent with this policy.

 **Business partners.** We may provide personal information to business partners with whom we jointly offer Services. In such cases, our business partner's name will appear along with ours.

 **Affiliates.** We may share personal information with our affiliated companies.

 **Advertising partners.** Through our Services, we may allow third-party advertising partners to set technologies and other tracking tools to collect information regarding your use of EA's Services and your device (e.g., your IP address, mobile identifiers, page(s) visited, location, browser information, time of day). We may also combine and share such information and other information (such as your de-identified account information, demographic information, hardware specifications, and past purchase history) with third-party advertising partners. These advertising partners may use this information (and similar information collected from other websites) for purposes of delivering targeted advertisements to you when you visit third-party websites within their networks. This practice is commonly referred to as "interest-based advertising" or "online behavorial advertising." We may allow access to other data collected by the Services to share information that may be userful, relevant, valuable or otherwise of interest to you.

If you prefer not to share your EA personal information with third-party advertising partners, you may follow the instructions on this page to change your settings: <https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBPRIVACYCA/US/en/PC/>.

 **Disclosures to protect us or others.** We may access, preserve, and disclose any information we store associated with you to external parties if we, in good faith, believe doing so is required or appropriate to: comply with law enforcement or national security requests and legal process, such as a court order or subpoena; protect your, our or others' rights, property, or safety; enforce our policies or contracts; collect amounts owed to us; or assist with an investigation or prosecution of suspected or actual illegal activity.

 **Disclosure in the event of merger, sale, or other asset transfer.** In the event of a reorganization, divestiture, merger, sale or bankruptcy, we may transfer all information we collect to the relevant third party and will obtain your consent to do so if required by law or contract.

 **Third-party plugins.** When third-party technologies or social tools are integrated into our Services, those third parties may collect information about your use of our Services. An example is the Facebook "Like" button.

 **User of de-identified information.** We may share de-identified or aggregated information with third parties, for instance your persona or game stats on leaderboards, or to show trends about use of our Services.

## 5\. Where We Hold Your Information

Personal information we collect may be stored and processed for the purposes set out in this Privacy and Cookie Policy in the United States or any other country in which EA, its subsidiaries, or third party agents operate. By using our Services, you acknowledge that your personal information may be transferred to recipients in the United States and other countries that may not offer the same level of privacy protection as the laws in your country of residence or citizenship.

EA's privacy practices comply with the APEC Cross Border Privacy Rules System. The APEC CBPR system provides a framework for organizations to ensure protection of personal information transferred among participating APEC economies. More information about the APEC framework can be found at <https://www.apec.org/Groups/Committee-on-Trade-and-Investment/~/media/Files/Groups/ECSG/CBPR/CBPR-PoliciesRulesGuidelines.ashx>.

Information is collected by our parent company, Electronic Arts, Inc. For information regarding the European Economic Area (EEA), United Kingdom and Switzerland, Electronic Arts, Inc. holds certifications under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield (which are available at [www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnuQAAS&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnuQAAS&status=Active)). When Electronic Arts, Inc. transfers information from the EEA, United Kingdom and Switzerland to other affiliates, agents or service providers that are outside the EEA, United Kingdom and Switzerland, it will do so in compliance with the 'Accountability for Onward Transfer' principle of the Privacy Shield.

## 6\. How We Protect Your Personal Information

Security of our players' information is a priority at EA, and we take a range of measures to help protect it, including encryption of sensitive financial information. Even so, no security measure is 100% perfect. This means we cannot guarantee the security of your information and do not assume any responsibility for the unauthorized use or access to your information under our control.

## 7\. Children

Protecting children's privacy online is extremely important to EA. Many EA online and mobile games and Services are intended for adults and do not knowingly collect any personal information from children. Meanwhile, other Services provide a different experience for players based on their age. When players identify themselves as being children we will: (1) not provide a path for them to share personal information, (2) collect certain information for limited purposes only, (3) block or restrict the child from accessing relevant Services, such as chat functionality; and/or (4) obtain consent from parents for the use of their children's personal information, all according to applicable law. When we say children, we mean under the age of 13 in the United States, or the minimum age in the child's territory. Through our mobile applications, your child will be able to receive local in-app notifications, which do not rely on any personal information.

Please note that if you are a parent or guardian and grant consent for your child to use EA's online or mobile games and Services, this may include such general audience communication services as email, instant messaging, and online groups, and your child will be able to communicate with, and disclose personal information to, other players of all ages.

If you are a parent and wish to revoke your previously provided consent, review information collected from your child or have that information deleted, contact the appropriate Privacy Policy Administrator for your country listed at [privacyadmin.ea.com](http://privacyadmin.ea.com/). If we become aware that a child has provided us with personal information, we will delete any personal information we have collected, unless we have a legal obligation to keep it, and terminate the child's account and/or revert them to the underage experience, as applicable.

Information collected is secured in a manner consistent with this Privacy and Cookie Policy. If we make material changes to how we use, collect, or share your child's personal information, we will notify parents by email or by in-game notice to obtain their consent for the new uses of your child's personal information.

We encourage you to talk with your children about communicating with strangers and disclosing personal information online. You and your child should review our Online Safety web page at <https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/OnlineSafety/US/en/PC/> for additional information about using the Internet safely.

Under no circumstances do we condition a child's participation in an activity—like contests—on the child's disclosure of more personal information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity. On certain sites, we may not permit children to participate at all, even if we have consent.

## 8\. Your Choices and Controls

We give you meaningful choices when it comes to important uses and collection of information. For example, if you no longer wish to receive marketing emails from EA, you may click the unsubscribe link included in the footer of every marketing email we send.

To exercise any of the rights listed below, you may contact help.ea.com or the appropriate Privacy Policy Administrator for your country listed at [privacyadmin.ea.com](http://privacyadmin.ea.com/) via email, postal mail, or phone. To protect your account security and personal information, you may be asked before exercising these rights to verify your account ownership, for example by reciting a code sent to the email address associated with your EA account to a customer support representative. Once you have verified your account ownership, you may also provide your written confirmation authorizing an agent to exercise these rights for you.

 **Your right to deletion.** You may deactivate your EA Account or delete the personal information associated with your account by contacting [help.ea.com](https://help.ea.com/en/) or your Privacy Policy Administrator in your country listed on our site at [privacyadmin.ea.com](http://privacyadmin.ea.com/). If you do so, you will no longer have access to the EA games or Services associated with your account. Note that EA may retain information needed to resolve disputes, enforce our user agreements, protect our legal rights, and comply with technical and legal requirements and constraints related to the security, integrity and operation of our Services. Otherwise, we will retain your personal information for as long as reasonably necessary to provide you with, create, and improve our Services, and to comply with the law.

 **Your right to access.** You can access the personal information we hold about you in a portable format. You can download a copy of your basic information by visiting your EA account and clicking the "Your EA Data" tab, or by visiting: <https://myaccount.ea.com/cp-ui/downloaddata/index>. To request access to additional data, please contact [help.ea.com](https://help.ea.com/en/). Before we process any request, we may ask you for certain personal information in order to verify your identity.

 **Your right to correction.** You can request correction of your personal information where it is inaccurate or incomplete. In some cases, we may provide self-service tools, such as those on the EA customer account portal at <https://myaccount.ea.com/cp-ui/aboutme/index>, that enable you to update some of your personal information.

 **Your right to opt out or object to certain processing.** You may have the right to opt out of the sale of your personal information to third parties, if applicable, or object to some processing of your data, where such requests are permitted by law.

For more information, visit: <https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBPRIVACYCA/US/en/PC/>.

You also may adjust your browser settings to block certain online tracking, such as cookies, as further described in Section 2.

You have a right not to receive discriminatory treatment for the exercise of the privacy rights described in this section.

## 9\. Third Party Services

Our websites and Services may contain advertising or third party services (such as the Facebook "Like" button or links to third-party websites). If you click on those links, including an advertisement, you will leave the EA website and go to the site you selected. If you visit a third-party website or use a third-party service, you should consult that site's or service's privacy policy.

## 10\. Changes to Our Policy

We may update this policy from time to time, so please review it frequently. We'll notify you of material changes via a notice on our home page ([www.ea.com](https://www.ea.com/)) thirty days before they go into effect. If we are required by applicable data protection laws to give you enhanced notice or seek your consent to any such changes, we will do so. You can see when this policy was last updated by checking the "last updated" date displayed at the top of this policy.

## 11\. Contact Us

If you have a complaint or question about this policy, please contact the privacy administrator for your region listed at [privacyadmin.ea.com](http://privacyadmin.ea.com/). Alternatively, you may contact our Data Protection Officer at [dpo@ea.com](mailto:dpo@ea.com). If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

The controller of the personal information processed under this policy is Electronic Arts Inc., 209 Redwood Shores Parkway, Redwood City, CA 94065. Electronic Arts Inc.'s representative in the European Union is Electronic Arts Limited, Onslow House, Onslow Street, Guildford, GU1 4TN, United Kingdom.

## 12\. Right to Contact a Data Protection Authority

If you have a concern about how we collect and use information, please contact us. You also have the right to contact your local Data Protection Authority if you prefer. Contact details for Data Protection Authorities in the EU are available at [ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm](http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/bodies/authorities/index_en.htm).

## 13\. Further Information

For more information and updates to this policy, visit [privacy.ea.com](https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBPRIVACY/US/en/PC/).
